subhasreemohapatra2019@gmail.com



LinkedIn Account in

# Portfolio =



# Summary

Enthusiastic and highly communicative IT professional with proven skills to adapt and work in various environments and domains for nearly eight years in the industry. Believer in continuous learning and adapting changes for improvements.

# **Skills**

- Python
- Java
- Data Analysis and Visualization(Power BI, Matplotlib, Seaborn)
- Anaconda(Jupyter Notebook)
- Scikit-learn Libraries
- AWS SageMaker
- GitHub
- Hadoop

- R
- SOI
- Machine Learning Algorithms
- Deep Learning (Tensorflow, Keras)
- Natural Language Processing
- Statistical Analysis
- Azure Fundamentals
- Scala
- Excellent Team Skills and Leadership

# **Work Experience**

# **MARCH 2021-PRESENT**

# Data Scientist/ Unearthed Solutions, Perth, Western Australia (Contract/Remote Working)

- Proposing key insights of various data analyses using statistical and visualizations and providing multiple solutions for the problem statement had been helpful for the customer to decide their plans as per the received feedbacks.
- Experienced in the collections and preprocessing of various sets of data to acquire solutions.
- Proven efficient implementation of Data Analysis and Machine Learning algorithms implementation for new predictive models and existing models and propose improvements for the existing machine learning models used by clients for better performance as per their current requirements, fetched an appreciation from the client.
- Enhanced the customer understanding of the performance of the models with thoroughly documented evidence and meanwhile increasing self-learning activity to address various queries of customers.
- Curiously engaging at various levels of implementation of the project as a part of self-learning and knowledge expansion.

#### **MARCH 2021-JUNE 2021**

# Data Science Intern / Montreal, Canada (Post Graduate Project)

- Working in an Agile process for using Machine learning algorithms, the Tensorflow approach and Keras trained models for classifications of Videos, proactively initiating deep learning solutions and designing them that resulted in a smooth delivery to the client before the project deadline.
- Demonstrating qualitative approach in collecting, cleaning, and organizing the data initiating the project from scratch.
- Implementation of clustering techniques over the videos and analyzing the similarities and dissimilarities of clusters formed helped the client to segregate the videos into more advanced classes.
- Acting as a point of contact between the team and client ensured smooth and transparent communication for better team coordination and customer satisfaction.
- Giving out insights of data using visualization techniques while addressing the concerns and issues related to data along with the resolution

#### **JULY 2011 - JULY 2019**

#### IT Analyst / Tata Consultancy Services, India

Flexibly working in agile environment and engaging across various domains such as Insurance, Manufacturing, and Media in various roles as per multiple projects and teams.

• Reduced customer time effort cost by 20% for multiple businesses flow by defining various Proof of Concepts and automating them using the UFT and ALM tools.

- Delivered thoroughly documented technical and business flow reports on the software development lifecycle process in the
  regression and functional implementation phase that reduced knowledge transfer and repetitive waiting time to understand
  codes and applications.
- Aligning and resolving the team concerns and blockers in phase to phase implementation of the project leading to gaining multiple customer appreciations.
- Leading, managing, and coordinating the team's ad-hoc activities and tasks by engaging with various cross-functional and cross-location teams, which gave leverage to my communication and team management skills.

### **Selected Projects:**

#### 1)Thomson Reuters- Regression:

Automated the business flows of the shipments, and transactions in SAP-SD in multiple streams of the project with feasibility
analysis, maintaining smooth flow with cross-location and cross-functional teams, demonstrating excellent analytical and
team coordination capability.

### 2) User Management System/ Sales Illustration System

• Understanding Business flows in Insurance Domain to provide suggestions for improvement, potential risks, feasibility analysis, change requests, and stakeholder management across various countries that increased team performance and customer index for feedback by 20-30%. Involved in regression testing and report development.

# **Education**

JULY 2019-JULY 2021

Masters in Data science / RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia

GPA: 3.6/4, Received Future Leaders Scholarship

JULY 2007-2011

Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering/ College of Engineering and Technology, Odisha, India GPA: 8.6/10, Recipient of Annual Scholarship for all years

#### Accomplished Publications/Projects (Few enlisted Data Science works)

Project Name	Brief Description of the Project
<b>Loan Status Prediction</b>	Building a model based on tree-based algorithms and Xgboost for classification of loan status of
	applicants. <u>Click here for Github Repo</u>
Vaccination for Pneumonia	A Power BI presentation for vaccination of pneumonia and its spread and types in Australia. Click
	<u>for Video</u>
Sport Image Classification	Building classification Neural models involving preprocessing of Images and
	ImageDataGenerator of Keras for Image Augmentation Click here for Github Repo
<b>Energy Consumption Prediction</b>	Predicting the energy consumption on an hourly basis of energy consumption using Gradient
	boosting, KNN algorithm, RandomTree approach with feature selection, outlier study,
	correlation study and statistical insights. Click for Github Repo
<b>Deceptive Visual Rectification</b>	Analysing visualization, reflecting, and rectifying it for clear understanding using R codes.
	Click for Github Repo
AudioPython	Developing PDFreader using python libraries for text to speech conversion and Tkinter for GUI
	design. Click for GitHub Repo

# Certifications

- Azure (AZ-900) certified
- Azure(AI-900) certified
- Azure(DP-900) certified
- Oracle Java SE 6

- Agile Scrum Foundation Certified
- ISTQB Foundation Certified
- ALMI LOMA certified

# About me

I have enthusiasm for volunteering and painting in my spare time. I was involved in TCS Maitri and mainly worked for underprivileged children and the old-aged as a Silver-rated volunteer. I am also a volunteer for mentoring and coaching children in an NGO in India that focuses on child education at no cost. I focus on teaching various subjects. The belief every child has the right to get a proper education. Nowadays, we also focus on educating the parents of the children. I had been contributing and guiding a family of 8K+ people for the change and awareness of education. Moreover, I have been using my time as a technology-based blog writer for Analytics Vidhya(A forum for data science) on medium.com.I enjoy portraying thoughts and open to feedback as it is also a great way of learning.